Human
geography.
Humans,
who
originated
from
earlier
primates
in
Eastern
Africa
three
hundred
thousand
years
ago,
have
since
been
migrating
around
Earth,
and
with
the
advent
of
agriculture
in
the
tenth
millennium
BCE,
have
been
increasingly
settling
Earth's
land.
In
the
twentieth
century,
Antarctica
became
the
last
continent
to
be
explored
and
settled
by
humans,
although
human
presence
there
remains
limited.
Since
the
nineteenth
century,
the
human
population
has
grown
exponentially
to
eight
billion
in
the
two
thousand
twenty
S,
and
is
projected
to
peak
at
around
ten
billion
in
the
second
half
of
the
twenty
first
century.
Most
of
the
growth
is
expected
to
take
place
in
sub-Saharan
Africa.
Distribution
and
density
of
human
population
varies
greatly
around
the
world
with
the
majority
living
in
south
to
eastern
Asia
and
ninety
percent
inhabiting
the
Northern
Hemisphere
of
Earth,
partly
due
to
the
hemispherical
predominance
of
the
world's
land
mass,
with
sixty
eight
percent
of
the
world's
land
mass
being
in
the
Northern
Hemisphere.
Furthermore,
since
the
nineteenth
century
humans
have
increasingly
converged
into
urban
areas,
with
the
majority
living
in
urban
areas
by
the
twenty
first
century.
Beyond
Earth's
surface,
humans
have
lived
only
in
a
few
special-purpose
deep
underground
and
underwater
presences
and
a
few
space
stations.
The
human
population
virtually
completely
remains
on
Earth's
surface,
fully
depending
on
Earth
and
the
environment
it
sustains.
Since
the
second
half
of
the
twentieth
century,
some
hundreds
of
humans
have
temporarily
stayed
beyond
Earth,
a
tiny
fraction
of
whom
have
reached
another
celestial
body,
the
Moon.
Earth
has
been
subject
to
extensive
human
settlement,
and
humans
have
developed
diverse
societies
and
cultures.
Most
of
Earth's
land
has
been
territorially
claimed
since
the
nineteenth
century
by
sovereign
states
(countries)
separated
by
political
borders,
and
two
hundred
five
such
states
exist
today,
with
only
parts
of
Antarctica
and
a
few
small
regions
remaining
unclaimed.
Together,
most
of
these
states
form
the
United
Nations,
the
leading
worldwide
intergovernmental
organization,
which
extends
human
governance
over
the
ocean
and
Antarctica,
therefore
all
of
Earth.